PradeepRaj

pradeeprajr93@gmail.com | +91 824 822 9854 | DOB: 21-Aug-1993 | Lives in Chennai

Online Portfolio link: https://pradeeprajr93.github.io/portfolio/

About me:

Full stack developer with more than 5 years of experience in Web application development, UX, and motion graphic design. I learn constantly and continue to be a lifelong learner to stay relevant and increase my areas of expertise.

Work Experience:

Infosys

Role: Specialist Programmer - L2

Mar 2020 – Present

- Designed and developed a CRM platform for a large US based insurance company using technologies like Angular 12, NodeJS, NestJS, Docker, Kubernetes
- Worked in an agile team and familiar with tools like JIRA
- Rated as "Exceeded expectations" during all my appraisal cycles till date

Role: Technology Analyst

Jan 2017 – Feb 2020

- Designed and developed multiple full-fledged web applications from scratch by mentoring a team of four
 - Designed and developed a chatbot testing platform using Angular 7+ and Spring boot.
 - Designed and developed a sophisticated video personalization studio. It has options to add annotations on top of a video, rich timeline control options, ability to export entire configuration as JSON file, etc.
 - Designed and developed a rich video player with personalization options and filed a US patent for the same.
- Developed various portals, demo applications for our products with complex layouts
- Interacted directly with clients from US, UK and shared deliverables on time

Role: Graphic, Motion and Web Designer

Feb 2016 – Jan 2017

- Designed product portals and studio prototypes using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- Designed motion graphic videos based on client requirements
- Used Adobe After Effects for designing videos
- Videos have been designed and delivered within timeline with quality

Role: Systems Engineer Trainee

Sep 2015 – Feb 2016

- Completed 6 months training at Infosys Global Training Centre, Mysore
- Trained in various technologies/tools like Python, Java, TIBCO and Web Technologies
- Completed the training with the High Performer badge

Education:

Bachelor of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Graduated: May 2015

(Mepco Schlenk Engineering College, Sivakasi) GPA - 8

Higher Secondary Education - 12th Grade Completed: March 2011

(Sri Vidya Mandir Matriculation School, Uthangarai) Percentage: 94.3%

Tools and Technology:

Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular 12, React, NodeJS, NestJS, MongoDB, Express, Jest, WebAssembly, Docker

Mobile: Progressive Web Apps (PWA), Flutter, Hybrid apps using NativeScript

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects (with scripting), Axure, C4D Lite

Cloud: Microsoft Azure (VMs, Blob storage, Cosmos), GCP (Compute), AWS (Lambda, TTS), Firebase, Dialogflow, Kubernetes

Accomplishments and interests:

- Filed three US patents in video personalization domain using web technologies
- Microsoft certified Azure fundaments (AZ-900)
- Won a design hackathon conducted by John Deere on digitization category
- Taken webinars to wider audience on concepts like PWAs, WebAssembly, UI Design, etc.
- RISD (Rhode Island School of Design) Certified Strategic Designer
- Certified with BEC Vantage, Global English (Level 6)
- Undergone a course on Ethnographic research to understand users' psychology
- Khan Academy, Pluralsight, Coursera, Udacity and books are my Netflix.
- Links I own: Open source and personal projects, design experiments, informative videos, thoughts and blogs.

Self-declaration:

I hereby declare that all the above furnished information is true to my knowledge.

Place: Chennai Sincerely,

Date: 03-June-2021 PradeepRaj